Lynda Ruby Ruiz

1542 Arch St, Berkeley, California 94708 559.631.6865 | lyndaruiz95@gmail.com

An enthusiastic professional who seeks a career in the tech industry. Great communication skills, flexible, and produces quality work while remaining organized.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

I am an engineer in practice, with experience developing end-to-end applications using Java, Javascript, Python, C, C#, LaTex, SQL and Matlab. I fuel my passion for technology and mathematics by continuously learning how to apply algorithms to solve mathematical equations while furthering my growth as an engineer.

EDUCATION

B.A. Applied Mathematics, Computer Science Concentration

June 2013 - May 2017

University of California, Berkeley

Relevant courses: Multivariable Calculus, Linear Algebra, Abstract Algebra, Numerical Analysis, Complex Analysis, Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs, Data Structures, Machine Structures, Artificial Intelligence, Efficient Algorithms and Intractable Problems

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Software Engineer I

June 2017 - Present

Ellie Mae Inc. - Pleasanton, Ca

- Responsible for developing, modifying, and unit testing software applications in local, networked, and internet based software programs
- O Support team server side needs through the maintenance and engineering of APIs
- o Create elegant client side applications through the coalition of modern day frameworks, such as Angular JS and React, with traditional frameworks of .NET to efficiently address customer needs
- o Integrate and merge existing legacy code with newly developed features across a growing platform

Student Coordinator May 2016 – May 2017

Cal NERDS – University of California, Berkeley

- o Managed over \$50,000 worth of invoices while updating vendors and students on payments and reimbursements
- Developed a purchasing order system that has increased efficiency and motorized future development
- o Analyzed monthly legers to interpret program spending data and create reports for the next semester budget
- O Worked on group and individual projects to benefit the program's 70+ members with academic and professional workshops

Berkeley Mini Math Tournament and Berkeley Math Tournament Problem Writer

January 2016 - May 2017

 $Berkeley\ Math\ Tournament-University\ of\ California,\ Berkeley$

- O Used LaTex to develop up to 20 different problems and solutions following 6th 12th grade curriculum
- o Worked with other problem writers to grade 100+ individual problems with a high accuracy to present results in as little as 1 hour
- o Traveled to Nanjing, China as a director for the first winter Berkeley Mini Math Tournament held in China for 120 participants

Theoretical and Computational Neuroscience Research Assistant

May 2016 - December 2016

Redwood Center – University of California, Berkeley

- o Applied sparse coding to understand auditory processing in the brain
- o Individually tested code on raw sound data to create spectrograms for future analysis
- Created sparse code to imitate the human brain using department's previous research gathered from cat neurons

Administrative Operations Student Assistant

September 2015 - July 2016

Student Affairs Office: Business Operations – University of California, Berkeley

- o Made purchases and refunds between \$70 \$5,000 for each organization and student on the UCB campus
- o Responsibly managed students' private information while efficiently sorting and scanning up to 100 student transcripts

International Student Advisor

June 2015 - August 2015

International Pre-Collegiate Program (IPCP) — University of California, Berkeley

- Mentored and guided 50+ international college students through their transition at UC Berkeley
- O Held weekly office hours that provided campus, professional, and personal support
- o Planned and executed college fieldtrips that provided information on Graduate programs in California

SKILLS & ACTIVITIES

Languages: Bilingual (English/Spanish)

Organizations: Cal NERDS, NSF CAMP Scholar, Lambda Theta Alpha Latin, Sorority Inc.